Guide to the Aleksis Rannit Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Subject files
  - Rannit, Aleksis
    - Writings, printed versions, 1969-1970 (Box 33)
      Includes a 1969 letter from Salme Purre, accompanied by copies of music manuscripts.
    - Writings, printed versions and typescripts, 1971-1974 (Box 33)
      Includes a 1974 letter from Salme Purre, accompanied by copies of music manuscripts.
    - Writings, holograph, typescripts and printed versions, 1972-1975 (Box 33)
    - Writings, typescript (copy) and printed versions, 1976 (Box 33)
    - Writings, printed versions (including copies), 1977-1979 (Box 33)
    - Writings, printed versions (including copies), 1980-1982 (Box 33)
    - Writings, holograph and typescript, 1983 (Box 33)
      Talk on Marie Under, holograph
      "Gedanken zu einer Definition der Poesie," typescript, corrected
    - Akna Raamistuses, working copy, typescript, circa 1985 (Box 33)
    - Interviews with Rannit and newspaper articles about Rannit, 1974-1978, undated (Box 33)
    - Unsorted writings, including drafts of poems, manuscript and typescript, 1947-1973 (Box 33)
  - Rebane, Imant, 1962-1972 (Box 34)
  - Reets, Paul, 1961-1972 (Box 34)
  - Retivova, Tatiana, 1977-1983 (Box 34)
  - Ridala, Esmo, 1958-1974 (Box 34)
  - Ristikivi, Karl, 1963-1976 (Box 34)
  - Roosma, Märt, 1946-1958 (Box 34)
  - Rossianskii, M.
    See: Zack, Leon
  - Saagpakk, Paul, 1969-1981 (Box 34)
  - Saks, Edgar, 1965-1982 (Box 34)
  - Samylova, Ol'ga, 1957-1968 (Box 34)
  - Santvaras, Stasys, 1960-1977 (Box 34)
  - Schapiro, Meyer, 1952-1980 (Box 34)
  - Sedykh, Andrei, 1963-1980 (Box 34)
  - Severianin, Igor' and Vera Borisovna Korendi, 1965-1967, undated (Box 34)
  - Shakhovskaia, Zinaida, 1970-1983 (Box 35)
  - Siebel, Julia, 1976-1979 (Box 35)
  - Siirak, Erna, 1966-1971 (Box 35)
  - Šilbajoris, Rimvydas, 1968-1983 (Box 35)
  - Sinkevich, Valentina, 1978-1981 (Box 35)
  - Slater, Lidiia Pasternak, 1961-1970, undated (Box 35)
  - Slonim, Mark, 1958-1971 (Box 35)
  - Snikere, Velta, 1967-1975 (Box 35)
  - Sologub, Fedor, 1904, undated (Box 35)
  - Stepun, Margarita, 1964-1970 (Box 35)
  - Still, James, 1982-1984 (Box 35)
  - Stravinskii, Igor, 1961 July 19 (Box 35)
  - Struve, Gleb, 1959-1978 (Box 36)
  - Talvik, Hermann, 1968-1980, undated (Box 36)
  - Terapiano, Iurii, 1960-1970 (Box 36)
  - Terras, Victor, 1965-1983; 2 (Box 36)
  - Tolstaia, Aleksandra, 1967-1979 (Box 36)
  - Torma, August, 1964-1971 (Box 36)
  - Truitt, Anne, 1974-1984 (Box 36)
  - Tulving, Rutt, 1964-1969 (Box 36)
  - Uibopuu, Valev, 1958-1981 (Box 36)
  - Under, Marie and Artur Adson
    - Letters from Marie Under and Artur Adson to Aleksis Rannit, 1946-1974; 6 (Box 37)
    - Third-party correspondence of and about Marie Under, 1931-1972 (Box 38)
    - Poems by Marie Under and Artur Adson, manuscripts, undated (Box 38)
    - Poems by Marie Under and Artur Adson, including translations, typescripts and typescript carbons, undated (Box 38)
    - Prose by Marie Under and Artur Adson, manuscripts and printed versions (including copies), 1954-1968, undated (Box 38)
    - Published poetry by Marie Under and Artur Adson, printed versions (including copies), 1966-1972, undated (Box 38)
    - Marie Under: La poétesse nationale de l'Estonie, introduction by Aleksis Rannit, drafts, typescript, undated; 2 (Box 38)
    - Essays by Aleksis Rannit about Marie Under, drafts and copies of printed versions, 1964-1974, undated (Box 38)
    - Other material relating to Marie Under, including articles, notes, and clippings, 1950-1973, undated; 7 (Box 39)
    - Photographs of Marie Under and Artur Adson, circa 1959-1980 (Box 39)
  - Usman, Lee, 1963-1979 (Box 39)
  - Valtman, Edmund, 1968-1982 (Box 39)
  - Veeber, Agate, 1954-1966 (Box 39)
  - Veem, Konrad, 1950-1981 (Box 39)
  - Vihalemm, Arno, 1954-1979; 6 (Box 40)
  - Viirlaid, Arved, 1966-1984 (Box 40)
  - Vladimirov, Leonid, 1970-1976 (Box 40)
  - Vladimirova, Lia, 1975-1976 (Box 40)
  - Weidlé, Wladimir, 1973-1979 (Box 40)
  - Weidmann-Kesküla, Ingeborg, 1961-1965 (Box 41)
  - Weil, James L./ Elizabeth Press, 1973-1984; 6 (Box 41)
  - Weinbaum, Mrs. Mark, 1973-1977 (Box 41)
  - Whitney, Thomas P., 1981-1982 (Box 41)
  - Wiiralt, Eduard (including copies of letters from Rannit to Wiiralt), 1939-1968; 4 (Box 42)
  - Willman, Asta
    - Letters from Asta Willman to Aleksis Rannit, 1961-1984; 2 (Box 43)
    - Third-party correspondence of and about Asta Willman, 1966-1984 (Box 43)
    - Writings of Asta Willman, 1964-1977, undated; 3 (Box 43)
    - Other material about Asta Willman, including articles and ephemera, 1966-1976, undated; 2 (Box 43)
  - Yakobson, Sergius and Elena, 1976-1979 (Box 43)
  - Zack, Leon, 1971-1975 (Box 43)
  - Ždanys, Jonas, 1976-1978 (Box 43)
  - Zlobin, Vladimir, 1965-1966 (Box 43)
  - Zurov, Leonid, 1969 (Box 43)
  - Zwibak, Jacques
    See: Sedykh, Andrei
- Printed Material, 1900, 1961
  - Bor, Matej, A Wanderer Went Through the Atom Age, 1961 (Box 45)
  - "Wana aasta ohtul," a service with responses, 1900 (Box 45)
- Restricted Fragile
  Conditions Governing Access
  Box 44 contains restricted fragile material. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
  - Material from boxes 6-43 (Box 44)